I was speaking to a group of about 300 kids,
كنت أتحدث لمجموعة من 300 طفل تقريبا
ages six to eight, at a children's museum,
تتراوح أعمارهم بين الثمانية في متحف للأطفال
and I brought with me a bag full of legs,
وأحضرت معي حقيبة مليئة بالأرجل
similar to the kinds of things you see up here,
تشبه تلك التي ترونها هنا
and had them laid out on a table for the kids.
وطلبت بأن توضع على الطاولة للأطفال
And, from my experience, you know, kids are naturally curious
ومن خلال تجربتي كما تعلمون فإن الأطفال فضوليون بطبيعتهم
about what they don't know, or don't understand,
للأمور التي لا يعلمونها أو لا يفهمونها
or is foreign to them.
أو ما هو غريب عليهم
They only learn to be frightened of those differences
فهم يتعلمون فقط أن يخافوا من هذه الإختلافات
when an adult influences them to behave that way,
عندما يؤثر عليهم الكبار للتصرف بهذه الطريقة
and maybe censors that natural curiosity,
أو ربما يراقب هذا الفضول الطبيعي فيهم
or you know, reins in the question-asking
أو تعلمون, قد يكون بجمح الأسئلة لديهم
in the hopes of them being polite little kids.
من باب الأمل بأن يكونوا أطفال صغار مؤدبون
So I just pictured a first grade teacher out in the lobby
لهذا فلقد تخيلت للتو مدرسة صف أول إبتدائي في البهو
with these unruly kids, saying, "Now, whatever you do,
مع هؤلاء الأطفال الصعبي المراس تقول لهم: "الان مهما فعلتم
don't stare at her legs."
فلا تحدقوا بأرجلها"
But, of course, that's the point.
ولكن بالتأكيد, فتلك هي المسألة
That's why I was there, I wanted to invite them to look and explore.
ولهذا كنت هناك. أردت أن أدعوهم لينظروا ويكتشفوا
So I made a deal with the adults
فأبرمت إتفاق مع الكبار
that the kids could come in without any adults for two minutes
بأن يسمحوا للأطفال الدخول دون الكبار لدقيقتين
on their own.
لوحدهم
The doors open, the kids descend on this table of legs,
وتفتح الأبواب, ينزل الأطفال لهذه الطاولة ذات الأرجل
and they are poking and prodding, and they're wiggling toes,
ويبدأون بالوكز والتحسس وتحريك اصابع الأرجل
and they're trying to put their full weight on the sprinting leg
ويحاولون أن يضعوا كامل وزنهم على أرجل العدو
to see what happens with that.
ليروا ماذا سيحصل
And I said, "Kids, really quickly --
وقلت: "أيها الأطفال, بسرعة,
I woke up this morning, I decided I wanted to be able to jump over a house --
لقد استيقظت هذا الصباح وقررت أن أكون قادرة على القفز فوق منزل
nothing too big, two or three stories --
ليس كبيرا جدا,من طابقين أو ثلاث
but, if you could think of any animal, any superhero, any cartoon character,
ولكن إن كنتم تستطيعون التفكيير عن أي حيوان أو صاحب قوى خارقة أو أي شخصية كرتونية
anything you can dream up right now,
أي شئ تحلمون به في هذه اللحظة
what kind of legs would you build me?"
فما نوع الأرجل التي ستبنون لي ؟
And immediately a voice shouted, "Kangaroo!"
وعلى الفور صرخ أحدهم "كانجرو"
"No, no, no! Should be a frog!"
"لا لا لا , يجب أن يكون ضفضع"
"No. It should be Go Go Gadget!"
لا يجب أن يكون أداة
"No, no, no! It should be the Incredibles."
لا لا يجب أن يكون أحد شخصيات "المذهلين"
And other things that I don't -- aren't familiar with.
وأشياء اخرى لم.. وليست مألوفة لي
And then, one eight-year-old said,
وبعدها, قال لي طفل في الثامنة
"Hey, why wouldn't you want to fly too?"
"ولماذا لا تودين الطيران أيضا" ؟
And the whole room, including me, was like, "Yeah."
وتحولت الغرفة بأكملها وأنا كذلك ل "ييييه"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And just like that, I went from being a woman
وهكذا فقط, تحولت من أن أكون امرأة
that these kids would have been trained to see as "disabled"
درب هؤلاء الأطفال على أن ينظروا إليها "كمعاقة"
to somebody that had potential that their bodies didn't have yet.
لشخص لديه القدرة التي لم توجد في أجسامهم
Somebody that might even be super-abled.
شخص قد يكون أيضا "ذو قدرة مذهلة"
Interesting.
ممتع
So some of you actually saw me at TED, 11 years ago.
بعضكم قد يكون راني في تيد منذ 11 سنة
And there's been a lot of talk about how life-changing this conference is
وكثر الحديث عن كيف استطاع هذا المؤتمر أن يغير حياة الكثير
for both speakers and attendees, and I am no exception.
لكل من المتحدث والمستمع,و لست إستثناء
TED literally was the launch pad to the next decade of my life's exploration.
تيد كان فعليا نقطة الإنطلاق لرحلة إكتشاف الذات لدي استمرت لعقد
At the time, the legs I presented were groundbreaking in prosthetics.
في ذلك الوقت, الأرجل التي كنت أعرضها كانت الرائدة في مجال الأرجل الإصطناعية
I had woven carbon fiber sprinting legs
وكانت لدي أرجل ركض مصنوعة من ألياف الكربون
modeled after the hind leg of a cheetah,
شكلت استنادا على الأرجل الخلفية للفهد
which you may have seen on stage yesterday.
والتي قد تكونوا رأيتموها على المسرح البارحة
And also these very life-like, intrinsically painted silicone legs.
وكذلك هذه الأرجل المصنوعة من السيليكون الأشبه بالحقيقية التي رسمت بطريقة جوهرية
So at the time, it was my opportunity to put a call out
وفي ذلك الوقت, كانت فرصتي لأضع استدعاء
to innovators outside the traditional medical prosthetic community
خارج نطاق الطب التقليدي لمجتمع الأطراف الإصطناعية
to come bring their talent to the science and to the art
ليأتوا ويحضروا مواهبهم لعلوم وفن
of building legs.
صناعة الأرجل
So that we can stop compartmentalizing form, function and aesthetic,
لكي نتوقف عن تقسيم الشكل, والوظيفة والجمال
and assigning them different values.
وإسنادهم لقيم اخرى
Well, lucky for me, a lot of people answered that call.
ولحسن حظي, الكثيرون استجابوا لهذا النداء
And the journey started, funny enough, with a TED conference attendee --
وبدأت رحلتي, مضحك بما فيه الكفاية, مع أحد الحضور في تيد
Chee Pearlman, who hopefully is in the audience somewhere today.
شي بيرلمان, الذي أتمنى أن تكون في مكان ما مع الحضور اليوم
She was the editor then of a magazine called ID,
كانت انذاك محررة مجلة اسمها : أي دي
and she gave me a cover story.
وأعطتني سبق صحفي في غلاف مجلتها
This started an incredible journey.
وهذا ما بدأ رحلة عظيمة
Curious encounters were happening to me at the time;
لقاءات فضولية بدأت تحدث لي في ذلك الوقت
I'd been accepting numerous invitations to speak
وكنت أقبل دعوات عديدة للتحدث
on the design of the cheetah legs around the world.
عن تصميم أرجل الفهد حول العالم
And people would come up to me after the conference, after my talk,
يأتي الناس لي بعد الندوة, بعد حديثي
men and women.
رجال ونساء
And the conversation would go something like this,
والحديث يدور على هذا الغرار:
"You know Aimee, you're very attractive.
"أتعرفين يا أني, أنت جذابة جدا
You don't look disabled."
لا تبدين معاقة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I thought, "Well, that's amazing,
فكرت "حسنا, هذا شئ عجيب
because I don't feel disabled."
لأني لا أشعر بأني معاقة"
And it really opened my eyes to this conversation
وفتح عيني لهذه المحادثة
that could be explored, about beauty.
التي يتم إكتشاف الجمال فيها
What does a beautiful woman have to look like?
كيف يجب أن تكون المرأة الجميلة
What is a sexy body?
ما هو الجسم الجذاب
And interestingly, from an identity standpoint,
والممتع, من وجه نظر لتحديد الهوية
what does it mean to have a disability?
ماذا يعني أن تكون لديك إعاقة ؟
I mean, people -- Pamela Anderson has more prosthetic in her body than I do.
أقصد, أشخاص مثل باميلا أندرسون لديها مواد اصطناعية في جسمها أكثر مما لدي
Nobody calls her disabled.
لا أحد يناديها بمعاقة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So this magazine, through the hands of graphic designer Peter Saville,
فهذه المجلة ومن خلال مصصم الجرافيك بيتر سافيل
went to fashion designer Alexander McQueen, and photographer Nick Knight,
توجهت لمصممة الأزياء اليكسندر مكوين والمصور نيك نايت
who were also interested in exploring that conversation.
اللذان كانا أيضا يودان استكشاف تلك المحادثة
So, three months after TED I found myself on a plane
لهذا, بعد ثلاثة أشهر من تيد, وجدت نفسي في طائرة
to London, doing my first fashion shoot,
إلى لندن لأداء أول تصوير أزياء لي
which resulted in this cover --
مما أدى لهذا الغلاف
"Fashion-able"?
قادرة على عرض الأزياء؟
Three months after that, I did my first runway show for Alexander McQueen
بعد ذلك بثلاثة أشهر, قمت بأول عرض أزياء لي للمصممة أليكسندر مكوين
on a pair of hand-carved wooden legs made from solid ash.
مرتدية أرجل خشبية منحوتة باليد مصنوعة من رماد صلب
Nobody knew -- everyone thought they were wooden boots.
لأ أحد كان يدري - الكل إعتقد أنها أحذية خشبية
Actually, I have them on stage with me:
في الواقع, هن معي هنا على خشبة المسرح
grapevines, magnolias -- truly stunning.
عناقيد عنب, ماغنوليا, بصدق مذهلين
Poetry matters.
للشعر أهمية
Poetry is what elevates the banal and neglected object
الشعر هو ما يرفع الأشياء المهمشة و المقصاة
to a realm of art.
إلى عالم من الفن
It can transform the thing that might have made people fearful
أنه يستطيع أن يحول الشئ الذي كان من الممكن أن يسبب الخوف لدى الناس
into something that invites them to look,
إلى شيء يدعوهم للنظر
and look a little longer,
والنظر أكثر قليلا
and maybe even understand.
وربما أيضا للفهم
I learned this firsthand with my next adventure.
لقد تعلمت هذا أول مع أول في مغامرتي التالية
The artist Matthew Barney, in his film opus called the "The Cremaster Cycle."
الفنان ماثيو بارني في فيلم التأليف "ذا كريماستر سيكل"
This is where it really hit home for me --
هنا فقط , شعرت بأني وصلت
that my legs could be wearable sculpture.
بأن رجلي ممكن أن تكون منحوتة تلبس
And even at this point, I started to move away from the need to replicate human-ness
حتى في ذاك الوقت, بدأت أبتعد عن الحاجة في تكرار الحس البشري
as the only aesthetic ideal.
كالبديل الإصطناعي الأمثل
So we made what people lovingly referred to as glass legs
فصنعنا ما سماه الناس بكل الحب "أرجل زجاجية"
even though they're actually optically clear polyurethane,
حتى وإن كانوا أساسا بوليوروثين واضح للبصر
a.k.a. bowling ball material.
المعروف بالمادة المستخدمة لكرة البولينج
Heavy!
ثقيلة
Then we made these legs that are cast in soil
وبعدها صنعنا هذه الأرجل الملقى بها في التراب
with a potato root system growing in them, and beetroots out the top,
مع جذور البطاطا تنمو فيها وبنجر من فوق
and a very lovely brass toe.
وأصابع زرع جميلة جدا
That's a good close-up of that one.
هذه صورة جيدة عن قرب لها
Then another character was a half-woman, half-cheetah --
هذه كانت شخصية ثانية , نصفها إمرأة والنصف الاخر فهد
a little homage to my life as an athlete.
القليل من الإجلال لحياتي كرياضية
14 hours of prosthetic make-up
14 ساعة من المكياج الإصطناعي
to get into a creature that had articulated paws,
استلزم لكي أتقمص كائن لديه كفوف واضحة
claws and a tail that whipped around,
وفك ويضر بذيل
like a gecko.
كالوزغة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And then another pair of legs we collaborated on were these --
وبعدها, الزوج الاخر من الأرجل التي قمنا بالعمل عليها كانوا هذه
look like jellyfish legs,
الأرجل الأشبه بقنديل البحر
also polyurethane.
أيضا من البوليريثاين
And the only purpose that these legs can serve,
والغرض الوحيد الذي تستطيع هذه الأرجل أن تقوم به
outside the context of the film,
خارج نطاق الفيلم
is to provoke the senses and ignite the imagination.
هي أستفزاز الحواس وإشعال الخيال
So whimsy matters.
لذا, للغرابة أهمية
Today, I have over a dozen pair of prosthetic legs
اليوم لدي ما يفوق الإثنا عشر زوج من الأرجل الإصطناعية
that various people have made for me,
التي قام بصنعها أشخاص مختلفين
and with them I have different negotiations of the terrain under my feet,
وبهم لدي مفاوضات عديدة للتضاريس التي تحت قدمي
and I can change my height --
وأستطيع كذلك أن أغير طولي
I have a variable of five different heights.
فطولي يتراوح بين 5 أطوال مختلفة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Today, I'm 6'1".
اليوم أنا 6"1
And I had these legs made a little over a year ago
وصنعت لي هذه الأرجل بما يفوق السنة بقليل
at Dorset Orthopedic in England
في دورسيت أورثوبيدك في إنجلترا
and when I brought them home to Manhattan,
وعندما أحضرتهم لمنهاتن
my first night out on the town, I went to a very fancy party.
ذهبت لأول رحلة لي خارج المدينة لحفلة فاخرة
And a girl was there who has known me for years
وكانت هناك فتاة تعرفني لسنوات
at my normal 5'8".
بطولي المعتاد 5"8
Her mouth dropped open when she saw me,
ذهلت كثيرا عندما رأتني
and she went, "But you're so tall!"
وقالت "ولكنك طويلة جدا"
And I said, "I know. Isn't it fun?"
ورددت "اعرف, أليس مسلي؟"
I mean, it's a little bit like wearing stilts on stilts,
بالرغم من أنه قليلا يشبه الإحساس بالوقوف على مطاولة فوق اخرى
but I have an entirely new relationship to door jams
ولكني الان لدي علاقة جديدة تماما مع أطوال الأبواب
that I never expected I would ever have.
ولم أكن لأتوقعها أبدا
And I was having fun with it.
وكنت مستمتعة بها كثيرا
And she looked at me,
فنظرت لي
and she said, "But, Aimee, that's not fair."
وقالت "ولكن أيمي, هذا ليس عدل"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
And the incredible thing was she really meant it.
والشئ العجيب أنها كانت تعني ما تقول
It's not fair that you can change your height,
ليس من العدل أن تغييري طولك
as you want it.
كما شئت
And that's when I knew --
وهنا علمت
that's when I knew that the conversation with society
أن الحديث مع المجتمع
has changed profoundly
تغيير بعمق
in this last decade.
في العقد الماضي
It is no longer a conversation about overcoming deficiency.
لم يعد حديثا عن التغلب على الإعاقات
It's a conversation about augmentation.
انه حديث عن الزيادة
It's a conversation about potential.
أنه حديث عن الإمكانيات
A prosthetic limb doesn't represent the need to replace loss anymore.
الأطراف الإصطناعية لم تعد تمثل الحاجة في أن تحل محل خسارة بعد الان
It can stand as a symbol that the wearer
تستطيع أن تمثل علامة للمستخدم
has the power to create whatever it is that they want to create
بأن لدية القوة لخلق أي شئ يود أن يخلق
in that space.
في ذلك الفراغ
So people that society once considered to be disabled
فالناس الذين في المجمتمعات الذين اعتبروا معاقيين
can now become the architects of their own identities
يستطيعون الان أن يكونوا مهندسوا شخصيتهم
and indeed continue to change those identities
وبالفعل, أن يستمروا في تغيير هذه الشخصية
by designing their bodies
بتصميم أجسامهم
from a place of empowerment.
من مكان التمكين
And what is exciting to me so much right now
والذي أعتبره ممتع للغاية في هذا الوقت
is that by combining cutting-edge technology --
هو بدمج التكنولوجيا المتطورة -
robotics, bionics --
الروبوتيات ، والبيولوجية الالكترونية
with the age-old poetry,
مع الشعر القديم
we are moving closer to understanding our collective humanity.
فنحن نتقدم أكثر لنفهم الإنسانية المجتمعة
I think that if we want to discover the full potential
أعتقد بأنه إذا أردنا أن نكتشف الإمكانيات الكاملة
in our humanity,
في البشرية
we need to celebrate those heartbreaking strengths
نحتاج أن نحتفي بهذه القوى الأخآذة
and those glorious disabilities that we all have.
وهذه القدرات الخلاقة التي لدينا كلنا
I think of Shakespeare's Shylock:
أفكر في شيلوك لشيكسبير
"If you prick us, do we not bleed,
"إذا وخزتنا, ألا ننزف
and if you tickle us, do we not laugh?"
إذا دغدغتنا, ألا نضحك؟ "
It is our humanity,
أنها بشريتنا
and all the potential within it,
وكل الإمكانيات التي فيها
that makes us beautiful.
هي ما تجعلنا جميلين
Thank you.
شكرا
(Applause)
(تصفيق)